When David was brought to the king to defend his cause,
he simply testified of how God had delivered him, saved him,
rescued him from the mouth of lion and bear, in his tender age.
Today, when we come out for the testimony it is nothing but the immediate goodness of God.
Remember the sickness you had in the past.
The same sickness others had and died,
while many others are still on the sickbed.
Life is in stages.
No matter how good you are,
no matter how clever you are,
there is always another level to reach for.
Those who are rich in every sense of the word, understand that life is a learning experience.
When you constantly strive to improve, you build character.
We Christians enjoy the opportunity to be a coach to others.
I've come to say how much I love You
I've come to say how much I adore You
Lord I'm not here to complain
About my many problems
By Your Spirit and Your grace
I'm confident You'll solve them
I'm here to say
I love You
I adore You
I'm here to say
I love You
I love to love You Lord
You may be seated.
Hallelujah.
Today's message: "My testimony".
We shall watch a documentary on who is T.B.Joshua, and the Synagogue Church of all Nations.
A lot has been said by people concerning how the church,
'Synagogue' came into being.
Some people questioned my foundation, my mentor,
my educational background and my calling as a man of God.
I am not showing this documentary because people questioned
my foundation, my background, my mentor,
my educational background, my calling as a man of God.
I am showing it because it is God's time. That is, it is an act of God.
Stay blessed and watch.
This is prophet T.B. Joshua at the prayer mountain.
Guided by the Holy Spirit prophet T.B. Joshua came to this prayer mountain to seek the face of God.
Like prophets of old, he fasted and prayed for forty days and forty nights,
as prayer and fasting open the door for God to enter.
It was at this very prayer mountain that prophet T.B. Joshua received divine anointing from God
to start his ministry.
As he raises his arms to heaven and then falls to pray, he receives a covenant from God
concerning his calling.
Only he and God know the divine message that was revealed to him at that moment.
Concerning this experience prophet T.B. Joshua said:
"I was in a trance for three consecutive days.
Then I saw a hand that pointed a Bible to my heart, and the Bible entered my heart,
and my heart immersed with the Bible immediately.
Then the awareness came, and I saw the apostles and prophets of old, with someone whose head I couldn't see
because He was tall to the Heaven and suspended, which I believe was our Lord - Jesus Christ
sitting in their midst.
I also saw myself in their midst.
After a while I saw a hand of the same tall man, I could not behold His face, which was glittering
with an unimaginable light.
But all the apostles - I could see their faces, particularly apostles Peter and Paul,
prophets Moses, Elijah, and others.
Their names were boldly written on their chests.
I heard the voice saying: "I am your God. I am giving you a divine commission to go and carry out the work of the
Heavenly Father".
At the same time, the same hand of the tall man gave me a small cross and a big Bible,
bigger than the one that had entered my heart, with the promise, that as I keep pressing in His time and name,
I would be given a bigger cross.
But if I fail the opposite would occur.
I also heard the voice of the same tall man, that I could not see His head, saying: "I am the Lord your God,
who was, and who is, Jesus Christ giving orders to all the apostles and prophets.
The same voice said to me: "I would show you the wonderful ways, I would reveal myself through you,
in teaching, preaching, miracles, signs and wonders for the salvation of souls.
Since then I have been receiving my visions every year according to my faithfulness to God.
A bigger cross means to me more responsibilities.
The Bible that entered my heart symbolized Spirit and Life - the Holy Spirit.
God's word is Spirit and Live.
He does nothing without His Word.
The book of Romans 8:16 says: "God's Spirit joins Himself to our spirit
to declare that we are children of God.
This divine anointing is performed by God Himself on all who have the wonderful privilage
of becoming His children.
It accompanies the conversion of those who trust in Christ.
Paul said that the Spirit dwells in every believer and His presence is the guarantee of our future glory in Heaven,
according to the book of 2 Corinthians 1:21-22
As a result of His indwelling presence we have the ability to become more like Christ, in accordance with
2 Corinthians 3:17-18.
We who are born of God have no excuse of remaining as we are.
We can be increasingly conformed to the image of Christ by yielding ourselves to God's anointing,
the Holy Spirit who dwells in our hearts.
Father, thank you for Your Spirit. Fill us with His Love and Power,
Change us into Christs' own image.
day by day and hour by hour.
Remember, Father gave us the Spirit to make us like His Son."
These are the pictures you will bring out and show people.
By the time the glory of God is revealed to the world and other countries start coming,
at that time, I will not have the time to come here again. I will have my own prayer mountain.
The man of God said that by the time the glory of God is revealed in his ministry, and people from other
countries start coming, he would no longer have the time to visit this prayer mountain,
and in the future he would have his own prayer mountain.
This is a picture of prophet T.B. Joshua praying for people after just having returned from a forty days,
and forty nights fasting at the prayer mountain.
During the early years of his ministry prophet T.B. Joshua did not have a vehicle to move around.
He walked almost everywhere he went for two years.
The children surrounding prophet T.B. Joshua are among those he gathered to follow him,
as he went to form first Synagogue Church of all Nations.
This is the first site and the first structure of the Synagogue Church of all Nations,
where prophet T.B. Joshua have just returned from the prayer mountain, lays the foundation of the church
located in Agodo-Egbe, Lagos Nigeria.
Prophet T.B. Joshua walks joyfully among the members as he lifts their faith with the Word of God.
Amen!
In fact, I don't know where to start. My coming into your midst is just to lay a foundation.
Today, we start the Synagogue here!
Worshipers gathered at the second church building of the Synagogue Church of all Nations,
that was built to accommodate the increasing number of members.
Prophet T.B. Joshua moves in their midst and prays for them.
Due to a violent thunderstorm the second church building of the Synagogue Church of all Nations
was completely destroyed.
After the second church building was destroyed another building was built,
this time using the wooden planks.
The first service was held at the new building of the Synagogue Church of all Nations in 1992.
The man you are seeing now, although difficult to recognize, is prophet T.B. Joshua at the age of 29,
ministering to the members.
This is prophet T.B. Joshua's first crusade in 1992.
Listen to him as he addresses the people in his local dialect.
Clap for Jesus.
Prophet T.B. Joshua prophesies to the people saying; we are in a small crusade now, but in the future
it is going to be big.
One might question why a church of just a small number of the outskirts of Lagos Nigeria should become
the Synagogue Church of all Nations
But this is a vision God had given to prophet T.B. Joshua.
Whatever situation you are going through serves a purpose.
It may be to stop you a while in order to reform you.
It may be to strengthen your desire.
Remember the man at the pool of Bethesda.
It may be to keep you for a new level in life.
We have seen people who had spent many years in the prison, later reaching the throne.
This is my song
Praising my Saviour
All the day long
This is my story
This is my song
Praising my Saviour
All the day long
You may be seated, thank you.
1 Samuel 17:37
“The Lord, who delivered me from the paw of the lion and from the paw of the bear,
will deliver me from the hand of this Philistine.”
David said it.
When David was brought to the king to defend his cause,
he simply testified of how God had delivered him, saved him,
rescued him from the mouth of lion and bear, in his tender age.
Today, when we come out for a testimony, it is nothing but the immediate goodness of God.
Remember the sickness you had in the past.
The same sickness others had and died,
while many others are still on the sickbed.
Life is in stages.
Here is prophet T.B. Joshua surveying the church premises after heavy rain,
had once again caused flooding.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is carrying a plank of wood to assist in rebuilding the church.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is packing sand along with members of the church to repair the damage,
that was caused to the first church's structure, due to the heavy rain storm.
Due to the increasing number of worshipers attending the church,
the Holy Spirit instructed prophet T.B. Joshua to move to a new location,
to accommodate the inflows of new worshipers.
In 1994 the church moved to Ikotun-Egbe, Lagos Nigeria.
This is the forth building of the Synagogue Church of all Nations.
The first building at the new site.
Thank you Jesus.
Inside the church are thousands of people joyfully receiving the Word of God.
After the service the man of God returns by motorcycle to his personal place of sanctuary,
his own prayer mountain, located 15 minutes from the church.
Here is prophet T.B. Joshua at the age of 32.
He was the overseer of the Synagogue Church of all Nations, while at the same time cleaning the toilets
of the church every day for 3 years.
One may ask the question; "why did prophet T.B. Joshua keep such a detailed record, right from the beginning,
of the life he lived?".
He is a man of vision, and his vision was inspired by the Holy Spirit.
It has God behind it for its accomplishment.
Every day for 3 years prophet T.B. Joshua also cleaned the sewers
of the Synagogue Church of all Nations by hand.
Life is in stages.
This record shows that there are different stages I went through in life.
Each stage served a purpose.
What are you going through as a Christian?
Tell you neighbor; "Are you a Christian?".
Whatever you are going through serves a purpose.
It may be to stop you a while in order to preserve you.
It may be to stop you a while in order to prepare you for the challenges ahead.
Tell you neighbor; "Whatever you are going through, as a Christian served a purpose".
Just a little while longer I wanna pray
Can’t get You off my mind
So I came to say thank You Lord
Just for loving me
Many times I do forget
Every need that You have met
O thank You Lord
I know You're showing me
You are there when I am down and out
You’re holding me
Your love is so amazing
O it changed me
Here I am with all I have
I raise my hands to worship You
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
For everything
For who You are
You covered me
You touched my heart
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
Here I am with all I have
I raise my hands to worship You
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
For everything
For who You are
You covered me
You touched my heart
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
Just a little while longer I wanna pray
Can’t get You off my mind
So I came to say thank You Lord
Just for loving me
Many times I do forget
Every need that You have met
O thank You Lord
I know You are showing me
You are there when I am down and out
You’re holding me
Your love is so amazing
O it changed me
Here I am with all I have
I raise my hands to worship You
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
For everything
For who You are
You covered me
You touched my heart
I wanna say thank You
O thank You
Hallelujah. You may be seated.
Whatever situation you are going through, serves a purpose.
It may be to stop you a while in order to reform you.
It may be to strengthen your desire.
Remember the man at the pool of Bethesda.
It may be to keep you for a new level in life.
We have seen people who had spent many years in the prison, later reaching the throne.
I don’t mind waiting
On You Lord
Thank you. You may be seated.
In the college of God, however brilliant you may be,
you will not be given double promotion. You will take every course.
In the University of God, however brilliant you may be,
you will not be given double promotion. You will take every course
because each course serves a purpose.
Imagine the rumors and gossip that spread as a result of this incident.
A prophet detained in a cell for taking drugs and harboring weapons.
However his enemies soon notice, that not even a detention in a cell and false accusations
would shake his faith in God.
To the wise this was a foolish thing, but God used it to reveal his purpose in the life of T.B. Joshua,
giving him the necessary experience and maturity to handle the greater responsibilities
God was preparing for him.
Like Joseph in the Bible; he has learnt what it is to be loved, hated, rejected, and slaved.
Accused and falsely convicted he bore everything that happened to him calmly.
This is the letter from the National Drug Law Enforcement Agency confirming the innocence
of T.B. Joshua,
and clearing him from the charge of drug dealing, for which he was detained in a cell for 13 days.
Remember, our enemy may rob us of our liberty and confine us in a prison cell,
but they cannot shut us out of the throne of mercy and communion with God.
Falsely accused of drug dealing by the (NDLEA) National Drug Law Enforcement Agency,
T.B. Joshua was arrested and held in cell for 13 days.
This is the first appearance of T.B. Joshua, having just been released from the cell.
He addressed the congregation thanking them for their faithfulness and love,
for standing by him in the hard times, referring to their unequal effort towards his absence.
You can see the man of God T.B. Joshua looking lean, having spent 13 days in a cell.
I am using this opportunity to thank you all for your unequal efforts towards my absence.
I am here to thank you all.
God Almighty will continue to be with you.
If you stay to yourself, “Why me of all this trouble, persecution, tribulation and all sorts'of things,"
I want you to now think back and ask, “Why me of all these spiritual blessing in my life?”
When you count the blessing of God in your life, doubt will fly away.
Even if you are suffering and you lack of this and that, remember the blessing of God
like food, shelter and many others you are enjoying today.
Having searched and found nothing against him, T.B. Joshua was released from the cell,
and the following Sunday appeared in the church service to thank the members and appreciate their love
and support during his absence.
Rather than to complain and query; "why me of all this trouble and persecution?" T.B. Joshua encouraged
the congregation to remember the spiritual blessings many are denied of, such as food and shelter,
that they can hold the very Word of God in their hands, and read it,
that they have the knowledge of His saving grace.
The man of God encouraged them saying; "when you begin to count your blessings your doubts will fly away".
In the College of God, however brilliant you may be, you will not be given a double promotion.
You will take every course.
In the University of God, however brilliant you may be, you will not be given a double promotion.
You will take every course,
because each course serves a purpose.
Right from the beginning, I knew that I must taste poverty in order to manage blessing.
Hundreds of benches and fans were installed inside the new church for the thousands of members,
that came daily to attend the services.
Not only did the prophet T.B. Joshua ministered to the congregation, he also gladly and faithfully
cleaned the fans and benches daily.
There were hundreds of them.
He cleaned them all.
As Colossians 3:23-24 says; whatever you do, work at it with all your heart, as working for the Lord, not for man,
since you know that you will receive an inheritance from the Lord as a reward.
It is a Lord Christ you are serving.
He is seen here cleaning the floor of the entrance to the church.
As is his practice, T.B Joshua regularly takes time out to share food with the children, and enjoy their presence.
Occasionally, T.B. Joshua can be found sitting among the children in their Sunday school class,
and visiting the babies in the nursing mothers section of the church.
He is an integral part of every department of the church.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is returning from the quiet moment of devotion in prayer at the prayer mountain,
to resume his activities at the church.
After conducting the Sunday service prophet T.B. Joshua would usually join the members in the canteen.
He serves water to the members.
This is one of services in the first building at the new site of the Synagogue Church of all Nations.
In fulfillment of the prophecy given by the man of God at the prayer mountain,
here you can see hundreds of people from around the world, who have come to listen to the Word of God,
that Jesus Christ has revealed to His servant - prophet T.B. Joshua.
Right from the beginning I knew I must taste tribulation in order to manage freedom.
Right from the beginning I knew I must taste condemnation in order to manage praises.
My objectives, right from the beginning, and my motives were determined at once.
I wanted what God wanted. I wanted if for the reason God wanted it.
Those principles anchored me through my teenage years.
They guided me.
They were the fountain stone of my life.
You raise me up
So I can stand on mountains
To walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up
To more than I can be
So I can stand on mountains
You raise me up
To walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up
To more than I can be
So I can stand on mountains
You raise me up
To walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on Your shoulders
You raise me up
To more than I can be
I don’t know why Jesus loved me
I don’t know why He cared
I don’t know why sacrificed His life
O but I’m glad so glad He did
You may be seated, thank you.
There were the fountain stone of my home, and the reason of our evangelists and pastors to be.
People of God, God has a time for everything.
A time to be born, a time to grow, a time to face persecution,
a time to overcome and a time to show the proceeds of victory.
Ask you neighbor: "what time are you in?".
Nothing happens by chance.
Unless you understand this, you will continue to murmur and despair
when what you want seems not to go the way you want it.
In the college of God, however brilliant you may be, you will not be given a double promotion.
You will take every course.
In the University of God, however brilliant you may be, you will not be given a double promotion.
You will take every course, because each course serves a purpose.
People of God, God has a time for everything.
A time to be born, a time to grow, a time to face persecution,
a time to overcome and a time to show the proceeds of victory.
During the raining season, heavy rain storms continue to flood entire church premises.
This is prophet T.B. Joshua in the rain in a dark-colored jacket.
Prophet T.B. Joshua works alongside the members to rebuild a wall that had been destroyed by the storm.
One life for Jesus is all I have. On live for Him is so dear.
He’s my love, my joy, my strength, my all. Without Him, I will fall.
Everybody desires a breakthrough,
whereas God sometimes uses disappointment
to keep us for a new level.
Everybody desires a breakthrough,
whereas disappointment is sometimes used
to prepare us for the challenges ahead.
Everybody desires a breakthrough,
whereas disappointment is sometimes used
to reform us for a better position in God.
Everybody desires a breakthrough,
whereas disappointment is sometimes used
to strengthen our desire for God.
Ask your neighbor; "Who knows what could have happened if your prayer for a better condition
had been answered?".
God’s time is the best time
My time doesn’t matter
Everything that has to do with God is fixed
There is a time to be born
And a time to die
God’s time is the best time
My time doesn’t matter
Everything that has to do with God is fixed
There is a time to be born
And a time to die
I choose to wait
Lord for Your time
Only for You
I choose to leave my past behind
I choose to wait
Only for You
God’s time is the best time
My time doesn’t matter
Everything that has to do with God is fixed
There’s a time to be born
And a time to die
God’s time is the best time
My time doesn’t matter
Everything that has to do with God is fixed
There’s a time to be born
And a time to die
I choose to wait
Lord for your time
Only for You
I choose to leave my past behind
I choose to wait
Only for You
I'm forever grateful to You
I'm forever grateful for the Cross
I'm forever grateful Lord to You
That You came to seek and save the lost
Hallelujah. Thank you. You may be seated.
Hallelujah.
When you know the principle of life, you will always reflect on life itself
rather than the situation you are in.
The principle of life is that nothing happens by chance.
Are you without strength, without smoothness of tongue, fast legs?
There is hope. Jesus is the hope.
This record is not saying I have arrived.
Remember our message here. Better is not good enough.
[congregation] The best is yet to come. [congregation]
As a Christian, the situation you are in serves a purpose.
You need to know the purpose it has, so that you stop grumbling, you stop to murmur.
In the Biblical characters from Genesis to Revelation,
nothing happens for nothing and nothing comes by chance.
In the Biblical characters, you will see how much pain,
how much hardship, trouble, tribulation, persecution, hatred, setback,
sickness, disease, they endured to come to a new level in life.
I know the persecutions I went through were the Lord's doing to strengthen my desire,
to keep me for a new level in life.
I know the hatred, the isolation, name-calling, intimidation, are the Lord's doing to preserve me.
The Lord used it to bring my real value.
The Lord used persecution to bring my real value.
When you are your real value, you will see life the way God sees it.
You will begin to see yourself the way God sees you.
You will work with God's projects.
You will get God's opinion about yourself and about others, when you are your real value.
Let someone say; "real value".
That is - what you are, not in the eyes of people but of God.
When you are your real value, you live the live of contentment.
A life without complain.
In the Biblical characters from Genesis to Revelation
nothing happens for nothing and nothing comes by chance.
In the Biblical characters, you will see how much pain,
how much hardship, trouble, tribulation, persecution, hatred, setback,
sickness, disease, they endured to come to a new level in life.
Welcome to a Sunday service at the Synagogue Church of all Nations.
T.B. Joshua is busy delivering an anointed message to the congregation.
What is that noise?
Where is the prophet going?
See the crowd rushing through the streets.
Where are they rushing to?
What we see is frightening.
Armed robbers are shooting on the streets outside the church.
See the man of God walking with boldness and confidence.
He has moved straight to the robbers.
See the scattered people.
What happened?
Well, let's follow the prophet and the crowd back into the church.
The prophet is making his way to the altar.
What's in his hand?
It's the gun.
The prophet has collected the arm robbers' gun.
This can only be the work of God.
[song] I know in whom I believe
I know in whom I serve
No evil principalities can change my mind
I know in whom I believe [song]
As the Bible says; "If you are a man of faith, fear of arm robbers in nonsense, fear of guns is foolish".
The purpose of this record – first, to show my total dependence upon God.
One life for Jesus is all I have. One life for Him is so dear.
He's my love, my joy, my strength, my all. Without Him, I will fall.
And to tell the weak that there is hope.
Jesus is the hope.
Are you without strength, without smoothness of tongue, fast legs?
There is hope. Jesus is the hope.
This record is not saying I have arrived.
Remember our message here. Better is not good enough.
[congregation] The best is yet to come [congregation]
It's my way of showing my thanksgiving.
Tell your neighbor; "No matter how good you are, no matter how clever you are,
there is always another level to reach for".
Those who are rich, in every sense of the world,
understand that life is a learning experience.
When you constantly strive to improve, you build a character.
We Christians enjoy the opportunity to be a coach to others.
Open your lips.
Ask God to remove the hands of evil spirit from the affairs of your life,
so that you can see life the way He sees it.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Amen.
This is your hour, this is your day, this is your time.
Open your lips.
Continue to ask God to remove evil hands from affairs of your life - prayer!
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
Don’t let my situation escape the anointing of God - prayer.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ we pray!
Amen.
This is your day.